
***********************************************************************************************************************************************************************
Advantages of MongoDB over RDBMS

Schema less − MongoDB is a document database in which one collection holds different documents. Number of fields, content and size of the document can differ from one document to another.

Structure of a single object is clear.

No complex joins.

Deep query-ability. MongoDB supports dynamic queries on documents using a document-based query language that's nearly as powerful as SQL.

Tuning.

Ease of scale-out − MongoDB is easy to scale.

Conversion/mapping of application objects to database objects not needed.

Uses internal memory for storing the (windowed) working set, enabling faster access of data.

***********************************************************************************************************************************************************************
Why Use MongoDB?


Document Oriented Storage − Data is stored in the form of JSON style documents.

Index on any attributexu

Replication and high availability

Auto-sharding:Sharding is a method for distributing data across multiple machines. MongoDB uses sharding to support deployments with very large data sets and high throughput operations. Database systems with large data sets or high throughput applications can challenge the capacity of a single server.
Cloud distributions such as AWS, Microsoft, RedHat,dotCloud and SoftLayer etc:-. In fact, MongoDB is built for the cloud. Its native scale-out architecture, enabled by ‘sharding,’ aligns well with the horizontal scaling and agility afforded by cloud computing

// One of its most significant features is that you can scale out your deployments quite easily, i.e., additional nodes can easily be added to the deployment to distribute data between them so that all data neednt be stored in one node. This concept is known as sharding, which when combined with replication, offers great protection against failover. So lets take a closer look at sharding and how it can be implemented.


Rich queries

Fast in-place updates

Professional support by MongoDB

***********************************************************************************************************************************************************************

Docker advantages:

Faster start time. A Docker container starts in a matter of seconds because a container is just an operating system process. A virtual machine with a complete OS can take minutes to load.

Faster deployment. There’s no need to set up a new environment; with Docker, web development team members only need to download a Docker image to run it on a different server.

Easier management and scaling of containers, as you can destroy and run containers faster than you can destroy and run virtual machines.

Better usage of computing resources as you can run more containers than virtual machines on a single server.

Support for various operating systems: you can get Docker for Windows, Mac, Debian, and other OSs.

***********************************************************************************************************************************************************************

Advantages of aws

*Easy to use
AWS is designed to allow application providers, ISVs, and vendors to quickly and securely host your applications – whether an existing application or a new SaaS-based application. 
You can use the AWS Management Console or well-documented web services APIs to access AWS’s application hosting platform.

*Flexible
AWS enables you to select the operating system, programming language, web application platform, database, and other services you need. With AWS, you receive a virtual environment that lets you load the software and services your application requires. 
This eases the migration process for existing applications while preserving options for building new solutions.

*Cost-Effective
You pay only for the compute power, storage, and other resources you use, with no long-term contracts or up-front commitments. 
For more information on comparing the costs of other hosting alternatives with AWS, see the AWS Economics Center.

*Reliable
With AWS, you take advantage of a scalable, reliable, and secure global computing infrastructure, the virtual backbone of Amazon.com’s multi-billion dollar online business that has been honed for over a decade.

*Scalable and high-performance
Using AWS tools, Auto Scaling, and Elastic Load Balancing, your application can scale up or down based on demand. 
Backed by Amazon’s massive infrastructure, you have access to compute and storage resources when you need them.

*Secure.
AWS utilizes an end-to-end approach to secure and harden our infrastructure, including physical, operational, and software measures.

***********************************************************************************************************************************************************************
advantages of mysql

1.    Data Security
MySQL is globally renowned for being the most secure and reliable database management system used in popular web applications like WordPress, Drupal, Joomla, Facebook and Twitter. The data security and support for transactional processing that accompany the recent version of MySQL, can greatly benefit any business especially if it is an eCommerce business that involves frequent money transfers.

2.    On-Demand Scalability
MySQL offers unmatched scalability to facilitate the management of deeply embedded apps using a smaller footprint even in massive warehouses that stack terabytes of data. On-demand flexibility is the star feature of MySQL. This open source solution allows complete customization to eCommerce businesses with unique database server requirements.

3.    High Performance
MySQL features a distinct storage-engine framework that facilitates system administrators to configure the MySQL database server for a flawless performance. Whether it is an eCommerce website that receives a million queries every single day or a high-speed transactional processing system, MySQL is designed to meet even the most demanding applications while ensuring optimum speed, full-text indexes and unique memory caches for enhanced performance.

4.    Round-the-clock Uptime
MySQL comes with the assurance of 24X7 uptime and offers a wide range of high availability solutions like specialized cluster servers and master/slave replication configurations.

5.    Comprehensive Transactional Support
MySQL tops the list of robust transactional database engines available on the market. With features like complete atomic, consistent, isolated, durable transaction support, multi-version transaction support, and unrestricted row-level locking, it is the go-to solution for full data integrity. It guarantees instant deadlock identification through server-enforced referential integrity. 

6.    Complete Workflow Control
With the average download and installation time being less than 30 minutes, MySQL means usability from day one. Whether your platform is Linux, Microsoft, Macintosh or UNIX, MySQL is a comprehensive solution with self-management features that automate everything from space expansion and configuration to data design and database administration.

7.    Reduced Total Cost of Ownership
By migrating current database apps to MySQL, enterprises are enjoying significant cost savings on new projects. The dependability and ease of management that accompany MySQL save your troubleshooting time which is otherwise wasted in fixing downtime issues and performance problems.

8.    The Flexibility of Open Source
All the fears and worries that arise in an open source solution can be brought to an end with My SQL’s round-the-clock support and enterprise indemnification. The secure processing and trusted software of MySQL combine to provide effective transactions for large volume projects. It makes maintenance, debugging and upgrades fast and easy while enhancing the end-user experience.